Guide to the Russell Van Nest Black papers, 1919-1968.
Black, Russell Van Nest papers
- Series V. Russell Black Consulting Reports
  - New Jersey
    - Seventh Annual Report of the New Jersey State Planning Board - War and Post-war Planning for the Year 1941, 1942 (Box 40, Folder 44)
    - Effective Zoning, 1944 (Box 40, Folder 45)
    - State Planning in New Jersey 1934-1944, 1944 (Box 40, Folder 46)
    - Land-Subdivision Guidance and Regulation in New Jersey and a Model Draft of Platting Rules and Regulations, 1946 (Box 40, Folder 47)
    - Parks and Recreational Land Use in New Jersey., 1965 (Box 40, Folder 48)
    - Development Plan for New Jersey: A Report Upon Planning Surveys, Planning Studies and a Comprehensive Plan for the State of New Jersey., 1950 (Box 40, Folder 49)
  - P-Z
    - "How to Plan for your Comfort, Happiness and Prosperity"for the Philadelphia Regional Planning Federation, 1930 (Box 40, Folder 50)
    - "A Report of the Preliminary Planning Study for the City of Ithaca, New York", 1924 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Comprehensive Planning Report for Borough of Princeton, New Jersey", 1929 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - "Recommended Changes in the Zoning Ordinance for the Borough of Watchung, Somerset County, New Jersey", 1939 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - "A Plan and a Zoning Ordinance for the Borough of Watchung, Somerset County, New Jersey., 1941 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - "The Hyde Park District, Dutchess County, New York State. A Report Upon Its Possibilities for Development as the United Nations Headquarters", 1946 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - "Zoning and Other Development Regulations for Readington Township, Hunterdon County, New Jersey", 1946 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - "Planning and Zoning for Mount Vernon, Ohio", 1946 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - "Planning and Zoning for Wayne Township, Passaic County, New Jersey", 1947 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Planning and Zoning for Winston-Salem, Forsyth County, North Carolina", 1948 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Trenton Metropolitan Area"by Black, Russell, Grubb, Eric, 1950 (Box 41, Folder 10-11)
    - "Official Report on Planning and Zoning for Metropolitan Trenton", 1952 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - "Future Use of Land Plan for the City of Trenton, New Jersey."by Black, Russell and Montney, Russell, 1954 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - "Park and Recreational Plan for Somerset, New Jersey", 1957 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - "Park and Recreational Plan for Somerset, New Jersey", 1958 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - "The Monticello Plan Summary of Comprehensive Report", 1958 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Village of Monticello, Sullivan County, New York", 1958 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - "Preliminary Studies of the Proposed State Route 206 By-Pass of the Borough of Princeton and Princeton Coop Road", 1960 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - "Revised Park and Recreational Plan for Somerset County, New Jersey.", 1966 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - "Redevelopment for the City of Trenton", 1952 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - "Ten Year Report Park and Recreational Plan", undated (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Pennsylvania: Allentown - Lower Makefield
    - "Planning and Zoning for Allentown, Pennsylvania", 1945 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - "Fourth Street Urban Renewal Project, Allentown, Pennsylvania - Eligibility and Relocation Report"by Black, Russell and Valet, John., 1959 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - "Revised General Plan for the City of Allentown, Lehigh County, Pennsylvania"by Black, Russell and Valet, John., 1959 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - "An Urban Renewal Program for the City of Allentown, Pennsylvania. by Black, Russell and Valet, John., 1957 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - "An Interim Report on the City of Bethlehem" by Clarke, Gilmore and Rapuano, Michael, 1937, undated (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - Cameron County. "An Analysis of Problems"by Black, Russell for the Pennsylvania State Planning Board, 1958 (Box 41, Folder 26-27)
    - "The Central Berks Regional Plan. A Report to the Central Berks Planning Commission", 1958 (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - "Zoning in the Central Berks Region"by Black, Russell, undated (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Borough of Doylestown, Pennsylvania. A Report"by Black, Russell, July 1954 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Borough of Emmaus, Lehigh County, Pennsylvania.:by Black, Russell and Tokmakian, Harold, May 1957 (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - "A Plan and Zoning Ordinance for Lancaster Township, Lancaster County, Pennsylvania."by Black, Russell, March 1940 (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - "Proposed Revision of Zoning Ordinance for Lancaster Township, Lancaster County, Pennsylvania. by Black, Russell, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 33)
    - "Proposed Revised Draft of Zoning Ordinance for Lancaster Township, Lancaster County, Pennsylvania"by Black, Russell, undated (Box 41, Folder 34)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Township of Lower Makefield, Bucks County, Pennsylvania"by Black, Russell, 1954 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Pennsylvania: Lower Paxton - Z
    - Bucks County Planning Commission " A Comprehensive Plan for Bucks County, Pennsylvania", 1961 (Box 41, Folder 36)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the City of Lebanon, Pennsylvania."by Black, Russell, August 1944 (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - "Planning and Zoning for Lancaster Township, Pennsylvania"by Black, Russell, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 38)
    - "Planning and Zoning for Lower Paxton Township, Dauphin County, Pennsylvania."by Black, Russell, January 1951 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "A Plan and Zoning Ordinance for Manheim Township, Lancaster County, Pennsylvania."by Black, Russell, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Borough of Morrisville, Pennsylvania"by Black, Russell for the Mount Joy Planning Commission., November 1952 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Borough of Mount Joy, Lancaster County, Pennsylvania", December 1945 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Borough of Mount Joy, Lancaster County, Pennsylvania." A report.by Black, Russell, May 1945 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - "Proposed Preliminary Draft of Zoning Ordinance for Ontelaunee Township, Berks County, Pennsylvania"by Black, Russell, June 1959 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Ontelaunee Township, Berks County, Pennsylvania"by Black, Russell and Tokmakian, Harold, June 1959 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania Planning., 1942 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      Subject and/or Contents: Harrisburg; Pennsylvania State Planning Board.
    - "A Picture of the Region", undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
      Subject and/or Contents: Philadelphia Tri-State District. Regional Planning Federation.
    - "Regional Plan for the Philadelphia Tri-State District. A Special Report: The Delaware River Bridge Approach", undated (Box 42, Folder 10)
      Subject and/or Contents: Bridge Committee of Regional Planning Federation Philadelphia Tri-State District
    - "Regional Planning and its Relation to Real Estate Development in the Tri-State District", undated (Box 42, Folder 11)
      Subject and/or Contents: Fund for Regional Planning of the Tri-State District
    - "Theory of Planning the Region as Exemplified by the Philadelphia Tri-State Plan"by Black, Russell, 1930 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - "Regional Planning: The Region - Past, Present, Future: A Digest of the Policies, Principles, Procedure and Findings of the Regional Planning Federation of the Philadelphia Tri-State District", 1931 (Box 42, Folder 13)
      Subject and/or Contents: Regional Planning Federation of the Philadelphia Tri-State District.
    - "A Master Plan for the Tri-State Region", undated (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - "By-pass Highways for the Traffic Relief", December 1927 (Box 42, Folder 15)
      Subject and/or Contents: Highway Committee of the Regional Planning Federation of the Philadelphia Tri-State District.
    - "Meadow Forest and Stream for Play, Profit, and Pure Water."by Black, Russell, April 1928 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - "Regional Planning and its Relation to Commerce and Industry in the Tri-State District", undated (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - "Regional Planning and its Relation to Railroads and other Utilities", undated (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - "Zoning Ordinance for Salisbury Township, Lehigh County, Pennsylvania"by Black, Russell, undated (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Township of Salisbury, Lehigh County, Pennsylvania."by Black, Russell and Valet, John., August 1959 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Borough of Schuylkill Haven, Schuylkill County, Pennsylvania. by Black, Russell and Valet, John., 1959 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - "A Survey for Planning in Schuylkill Haven. An Urban Planning Assistance Project"by Black, Russell, and Valet, John, undated (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - "Supplement to Report, Planning and Zoning for the Borough of Schuylkill Haven."by Black, Russell., November 1959 (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - "Planning and Zoning for the Township of South Whitehall, Lehigh County, Pennsylvania"by Black, Russell and Valet, John., July 1960 (Box 42, Folder 24-25)
    - "Criteria and Planning for Public Works"by Black, Russell., June 1934 (Box 42, Folder 26)
      Subject and/or Contents: Research for Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works, Washington.
- Series VI. American Institute of Planners
  - American City Planning Institute: Business File, 1934 (Box 42, Folder 27)
    Subject and/or Contents: John Nolen; Fred Bigger; Flavel Shurtleff; Harold Buttenheim; Jacob Crane; Alfred Bettman; Arthur Comey.
  - American City Planning Institute: Business File, 1935 (Box 42, Folder 28)
    Subject and/or Contents: Fred Bigger; Alfred Bettman; Howard Menhinick; Jacob Crane; John Nolen; Flavel Shurtleff; Harold Lewis. Constitution.
  - American City Planning Institute, 1936-1937 (Box 42, Folder 29)
    Subject and/or Contents: National Resources Committee Consultant Rate. Business. Frederick Bigger; Alfred Bettman; Tracy Augur; Howard Menhinick; Harold Lautner; Jacob Crane; Earle Draper; Arthur Comey; Harland Bartholomew; L. Deming Tilton; Frederick J. Adams; Henry Hubbard.
  - American City Planning Institute, 1936-1937 (Box 42, Folder 30)
    Subject and/or Contents: National Resources Committee Questionnaire. Alfred Bettman; L. Deming Tilton; Walter Bluchur; Tracy Augur; John Nolen; Arthur Comey; Jacob Crane; Flavel Shurtleff; Harold Lewis.
  - American City Planning Institute, 1937-1938 (Box 42, Folder 31)
    Subject and/or Contents: Frederick Adams; Tracy Augur; Howard Strong.
  - American City Planning Institute Correspondence, 1958 (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - American Institute of Planners 50th Anniversary, 1964-1966 (Box 42, Folder 33)
    Subject and/or Contents: Materials. Harland Bartholomew; Paul Opperman.
  - American Institute of Planners Anniversary Program, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - American Institute of Planners Anniversary Book, History of Planning in the U.S. by Mel Scott., 1963-1968 (Box 42, Folder 35)
    Subject and/or Contents: Harland Bartholomew; Mel Scott; John Reps; Tracy Augur; Paul Opperman; Thomas Grouy.
  - American Institute of Planners (Philadelphia Regional Chapter), 1956-1960 (Box 42, Folder 36)
  - American Institute of Planners Committee Reports, 1960-1962 (Box 42, Folder 37)
  - American Planning and Civic Association, 1938 (Box 42, Folder 38)
  - From Russell Van Nest Black, 1937, Files Institute Data, 1936-1937 (Box 42, Folder 39)
    Subject and/or Contents: Reference Data. Alfred Bettman; Tracy Augur.
  - Book Material, undated (Box 42, Folder 40)
    Subject and/or Contents: Articles; Clippings
  - Black, Russell - "The Founders" from American Institute of Planners 50th Anniversary Commemorative Booklet., undated (Box 42, Folder 41)
  - Committee Reports, 1936-1937 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    Subject and/or Contents: Alfred Bettman; Harold Lautner; H.V. Hubbard; Tracy Augur.
  - Educational Plans, 1938 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    Subject and/or Contents: Adams, Frederick - "Planning Education for Pupils in Grade School High School."; Blaisdell, Donald - "Planning Education for Public Officials.". National Conference on Planning. Natinoal Association of Housing Officials.
  - Institutional Committees, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    Subject and/or Contents: Tracy Augur; Walter Blucher; Alfred Bettman; T.V. Hubbard; Howard Menhinick; Tracey Augur; Harland Barthohomew
  - Institutional Committees, 1951-1957 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Institutional Committee Reports, 1938 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    Subject and/or Contents: American City Planning Institute 1938 elections. Tracy Augur; L. Deming Tilton; Harold Lautner; Alfred Betteman.
  - Institute Meetings, Programs and Minutes, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Subject and/or Contents: Jacob Crane; Howard Menhinick; Eifel Saarinew; Ramond Unwin; Tracy Augur; Henry Hubbard; Walter Bluckner; Bilmore Clarke; Flavel Shurtleff; John Nolen; John Nolen, Alfred Bettman.
  - Institute Membership Applications, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Subject and/or Contents: Howard Menhinick; Jacob Crane; L. Deming Tilton; Gilmore Clarke; Tracy Augur.
  - Membership Committee, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    Subject and/or Contents: Aurthur C. Comey; Hoard Menhinick.
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - The Planners Journal, 1936-1938 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Programs and Conference Arrangements, 1937-1938 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    Subject and/or Contents: American City Planning Institute. Tracy Augur Frederick Bigger; Walter Blucher
  - Vignette Material American Institute of Planners 50th Anniversary Booklet, 1963-1965 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    Subject and/or Contents: Research Information. Harland Bartholomew; Harry Brainerd; Flavel Shurtleff; Tracy Augur; Ladislas Sego; Harold Lewis.
  - World's Fair Committee, 1936-1937 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    Subject and/or Contents: America City Planning Institute- World's Fair Exhibit Committee. Clarence Stein; Harold Buttenheim; Lawrence M. Orton; Robert Kohn
  - World's Fair Committee, 1938 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    Subject and/or Contents: Civic Films - "The City". Tracy Augur; Clarence Stein; Harold Buttenheim; Frederick Ackerman.
  - "Planning and the Planning Profession, the Past 50 Years 1917-1967, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - American Institute of Planners. Armand Tibbitts., 1968-1969 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - AIP Membership, 1925 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - American Institute of Planners Proceedings, October 19-21, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 3)
- Series VII. Manuscripts and Research
  - Literary Manuscripts by Russell Black
    - "Aesthetics of Zoning" The Annals of the American Academy, undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - "After War- What?" New Jersey Municipalities., March 1942 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - "An Act to Create a Post-War Planning Committee and Describe its Duties and Appropriating Funds for its Purposes."., February 18, 1943 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - "The Architect, Engineer, and Landscape Architect in the City and Regional Planning" Joing Meeting of Architectural League and New York Chapter of American Society of Landscape Architects. NYC, June 15, 1944 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - The Axis of Chicago by Bennett, Parsons and Frost, Housing Magazine, undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - "Basic Surveys for City Plan and Their Use," American Society of Civil Engineers October 6, 1932; "A Better Case for City Planning, The Need for its Making, and A Few Suggestions as to What the American City Planning Institute can do About it," February 3, 1933., 1932-1933 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - "Can Intelligent Zoning be Done Without a Comprehensive City Plan? April 1928; "Central City Planning" The Pennsylvania Commercial Secretaries Association, March 21, 1946; Chief Problems in State Planning," Cornell College of Architecture, April 29, 1936; "The City Plan Insured," The American City 1923; "The City Planner Looks at the Inner-City Church," Allentown Area Council of Churches, October 19, 1958; "Review." City Planning and Housing by Wernen Hegemann Volume II. "Political Economy and Civic Art", Edited by Nanda Anslen.; "City Planning and Urban Redevelopment in National Defense." Architecture Forum, May 12, 1954; "Comments on State Planning" March 18, 1936; "The Composite profession of Planning." American Institute of Planners' Journal; The County - An Effective Unit for Planning." Better Roads Magazine., 1923-1958 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - "Civic Planning Comments", 1934-1935 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - "Civic Planning Comments", 1931-1934, 1941-1942 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Review of "Design of Residential Areas" by Thomas Adams, National Municipal Review., undated (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - "The Economic Aspects of Suburbanization Bersus Centralization of Cities" January 21, 1944; "Effective Planning and How It May Be Accomplished" American City Planning Institute, June 22, 1930, 1930,1944 (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - "A Few Governing Principles of Regional Planning as Observed in the Philadelphia Tri-State District." American City Magazine May 1927; "For Release to All Newspapers of County upon Date of Taking Action Toward Starting Planning Study"; "Friends of Hightstown"; "Function of the City Engineer in City Planning," 1937 Annual Convention of the New Jersey State League of Municipalities at Atlantic City, November 18, 1937; "The Fucure of Land Subdivision" Harland Bartholomew January 16, 1936.; "The Future of Redlands and Its Relation to a City Plan" Rotarian Club Luncheon Talk, December 7, 1922., 1922-1927 (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - "Memorandum- The Garden City Versus Subsistence Homesteads"; "General Nature and Scope of the Planning Job in Philadelphia." Philadelphia City Planning Commission, June 23, 1943; "Good Planning is the Best Insurance for New Housing or More Enduring Housing Through Better Planning," The National Housing Committee; "The Growth and Development of Cities with Particular Respect to the Factors Underlying the Centralization and Decentralization of Population," Research Department of the University of Pennsylvania by the Regional Planning Federation of the Philadelphia Tri-State District., 1943; undated (Box 43, Folder 25)
    - "A Heritage We can All Afford to Lose"; "Highway Protection in New Jersey. New Jersey's Expensive Orphans- Its State Highways." Daily News; "Hightstown Letters" Numbers 1-3; How to Plan and Pay for the Safe and Adequate Highways we need." The General Motors Better Highway Contest; "A Hundred Billion Man- Hour Job Goes Begging", undated (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - "Impact of the United States Steel Corporation's Fairless Works on Regional Planning and Development Needs. " City Planning Division of the American Society of Civil Engineers, June 16, 1954; "Discussion of Arthur Comey's Integration of a Regional Plan."; "Integration of Trunch Highways with Secondary Streets and Roads," Planning Division of the American Road Builders Association, January 29, 1941; "Is Social Economic Planning Being Over-Empahsized in Current State Planning Porgrams?" National Planning Conference, Detroit, June 1937., 1937-1954 (Box 43, Folder 27)
    - "Joint Planning Board Aids Orderly Development" in The American City, February 1952 (Box 43, Folder 28)
    - "Land Development and Housing"; "Land Subdivision" Second Annual Surveying Conference at Rutgers University, May 18, 1940; "Large Scale Housing and The City Plan," National Conference in Planning at Richmond, Virginia, May 4, 1936; "Let us Stop Talking. We must act on Urban Reconstruction," Panel Discussion, Annual Conference, New Jersey Federation of Planning Boards, April 18, 1942; "Letter to the Editor" Journal of the American Institute of Planners. January 1968.; "Letter to the Editor." Pennsylvania Plans. June 1951; "Letter to the Editor: American Society of Planning Officials, September 1941, December 1963; "The Local Planning Board's Job in Preparedness." County and Municipal Planning Boards in New Jersey; "Local and State Cooperation in the Post-War Planning." New Jersey Federation of Official Planning Boards Meeting, November 1943, 1936-1968 (Box 43, Folder 29)
    - "Maintenance of Planning Standards in the Housing Emergency Program" American Institute of Planners, Tennessee October 19, 1946; "Making and Carrying Out the City or Regional Plan" Cornell University Lecture, February 23, 1931, May 3 1937; "Making of the Plan" National Conference on Planning at Cincinnati, May 20, 1935; "Manpower and Brain - Power in City and Regional Planning," Joint Meeting of the New York Architectural League and the New York Chapter of American Society of Landscape Architects; "Maps and Surveys for Planning" American Congress on Surveying and Mapping; "A Master Plan for Recreation in New Jersey.: Third Annual Meeting New Jersey Parks and Recreation Association, October 25, 1940; "Material Required for a Regional Planning Study"; "The Mercer County Plan" 1932; "Million Dollar Community Contest", The Atlantic, August 13, 1936; "Review" Modern Town and Country Planning: A History of and Introduction to the Study of the Law and Practice of Modern Town and Country Planning in Great Britain. Jamis W.R. Adams; "Multiple Use of Public Lands." New Jersey Section of the American Waterworks Association at New Brunswick, New Jersey. February 7, 1940; "Municipal Planning in New Jersey." New Jersey Planning Conference. March 18, 1936; "Must Planning go on the Shelf During a Depression" City Planning Division of the American Society of Civil Engineers. January 17, 1935; " My Platform". American City Planning Institute in Annual Meeting at Washington, D.C. January 18-19, 1936, 1931-1946 (Box 43, Folder 30)
    - "Discussion of Papers by Harlean James and Charles H. Cleney." National Conference on Planning, San Francisco, July 10, 1940; "National Planning 1942" American Society of Landscape Architects; "Nature, Purpose and Cost of County Planning in Pennsylvania," October 14, 1950; "Needed- A Better Basis for City and Regional Planning"; "Neglected Opportunities. Every Neighborhood, Every City, Every Community, Loses Something Through Failure to Plan" Civic Number of "Club Women's Magazine," December 8, 1939; "Review" Neighbourhoods of Small Homes, Robert Whitten and Thomas Adams. Harvard City Planning Studies; "The New American Falls, Idaho" League of California Municipalities; "New Jersey's First Comprehensive County Plan."; "New Jersey's Heritage- How Shall we Treat it." April 20, 1936; "New Jersey Moves Ahead with Local Planning and Zoning but few Municipalities are yet Taking Full Advantage of the Legislated Powers." New Jersey League Magazine; "Discussion of Paper by D.H. Sawyer New Opportunities for the Engineer in City Planning" City Planning Section, A.S.C.E., Chicago June 30, 1933; "Notes on School Planning and State Planning Boards and Their Relation to Public School Development" Better School Building Planning, Atlantic City, February 26, 1935; "Notes for the Unemployment Forum" January 9, 1936., 1933-1950, undated (Box 43, Folder 31)
    - "The Objectives of State Planning"; "Organization and Administration of a Planning Department"; "Organization and Legislation for a County Planning," Annual Conference of the American Road Builders; Association, Detroit, January 12, 1932; "A Proposal for the Organization and Operation of a Regional Council in a Metropolitan Area." January 14, 1943; "Outdoor Recreational Facilities in the Philadelphia-Camden District"; "Discussion of Paper 'Our State parks and Forests'" Presented by Charles B. Wilber, 1932, 1943, undated (Box 43, Folder 32)